当剧痛穿透身体  她发出惨叫
She screamed as the pain ripped through her,
呼吸沉重  她心想
and in between each labored breath, she thought,
我绝不能在布朗克斯区的地铁里
there is no way in hell I am having this baby
生下这个孩子
on a subway train in the Bronx.
你都记下来了吗
Did you get all that?
你真的是在地铁里生下你儿子的吗
So you actually gave birth to your son on the metro?
不
No.
不是的
She didn't.
她也没在生我前一周跑马拉松
She also didn't run a marathon the week before she had me
或者是在怀胎九月时暴打了一个劫匪
or beat up a mugger while nine months pregnant.
这叫艺术加工  儿子
It's called dramatic license, darling.
应该叫夸大其辞
Actually, it's called wild exaggeration.
艺术加工只适用于写作
Dramatic license applies to writing.
我就是在写作呢
And that's what I'm doing.
这是马库斯
This is Marcus,
我跟你提过的那个超级棒的年轻剧作家
this fabulous young playwright I told you about,
他在帮我编写我的独角戏剧本
who's helping me put together my one-woman show.
卡塞尔先生  我是你的超级粉丝
Mr.Castle, I'm a huge fan.
能来到这里就像美梦成真一样
Just being in this office is a dream come true.
对我来说也一样  一样
For me, too. For me, too.
只是我在我的梦里  通常...
Only in my dreams, I'm...
只有我一个人
usually by myself.
我们只是感觉这房间有激发创造力的能量
We just felt that this room had the best creative juju.
是啊  是啊
Oh, it does. It does.
我在这里写了二十本畅销书
Yeah, I wrote 20 best sellers in here.
是啊
Right.
我还想再写一本
I'd like to write another one.
现在就想
Now.
不能等会儿吗  儿子
Oh, can't it wait, dear?
我们刚刚在对第一幕做最终修改
We're just putting the final touches on act one--
描述的是  我怎样克服工作和
You know, where I overcome the challenges of being
单亲母亲的双重挑战
a single, working mother.
你知道你写的内容都是杜撰的吧
You know you're writing a work of fiction, right?
卡塞尔
Castle.
先是阿丽克西斯在蕾妮那里实习  谢谢
First Alexis is interning for Lanie. Thank you.
现在我妈又占用了我的办公室
Now my mother is taking over my office.
我感觉我的整个生活受到了侵扰
I feel like my whole life is being invaded.
你会习惯的  我就是这么过来的
You'll get used to it. I did.
这是两码事
It is not the same thing.
好吧  有些类似  但是没那么烦人嘛
Okay, it's similar, just much less invasive.
蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
这里是什么情况
So what do we got here?
问得好
That's a good question.
我能告诉你的是
I can tell you this much--
从尸温和凝血情况来看
Based on body temp and lividity,
死者死于十点到午夜之间
our victim died between 10:00 and midnight.
爪印
Claw marks?
她被野兽袭击了吗
She was attacked by an animal?
她死前在逃跑
Well, she was running from something.
脚下沾有泥土
She's got dirt on her feet.
中央公园有什么野兽能把人咬死
What animal in central park could maul a person to death?
还不一定是这样呢
I'm not even sure that's what happened.
撕裂伤口看起来很浅而且不致命
These lacerations look shallow, nonlethal,
不过我得到把尸体送回停尸间
but I won't know exactly what killed her
才能确认死因
until I get her back to the morgue.
知道她身份吗
Do you have an I.D.?
没有钱包或手袋  所以没法辨认身份
No wallet or purse, so we don't know who she is.
还不明显吗  难道只有我发现了吗
Isn't it obvious? I mean, am I the only one seeing this?
什么
What?
红斗篷  森林  野兽袭击
Red cloak, in the woods, animal attack.
她是小红帽
She's little red riding hood.
好啊  卡塞尔  我会全面通缉大灰狼的
Great, Castle. I'll call in an A.P.B. for the big bad wolf.
你有更好的想法吗
You have a better theory?
莱恩
Hey, Ryan.
你能去问下调度
Do you think you could call dispatch,
是否接到公园附近
see if there any reports of a violent animal
有猛兽出没的报告
running around the park?
比如很大很灰的狼吗
Like a wolf, a big bad one?
你也来这套
Really?
这完全就是我心里小红帽的形象
That is exactly how I pictured her.
真让人毛骨悚然
It's freaky.
小时候我姐姐就读小红帽我听
My older sister used to read me that story.
好了  等你回忆完你的童年之后
Okay, when you're done reliving your childhood memories,
能在这附近搜寻下
do you also think that you could canvass the area
目击证人或者认识她的人吗
for witnesses and anyone that might know her name?
而且我打赌她肯定不叫小红帽
And I bet you it's not gonna be little red riding hood.
马上去
On it.
"这样才能一口吃掉你呀
"'All the better to eat you with.'
大灰狼一说完
No sooner had the wolf said these words
就突然跳起来把可怜的小红帽
when he leaped up and gobbled down
吞进了肚子"
poor little red riding hood."
好消息是  这只狼会说话
Well, the good news is, the wolf can talk.
只要我们找到他  我们就能让他招供
So if we can find him, we might be able to get a confession.
是啊  只是在原版故事中
Yeah, except in the original story,
大灰狼没有杀死小红帽
the wolf doesn't kill little red riding hood.
猎人剪开大灰狼的肚子救出了她
The huntsman cuts her out of the wolf's stomach,
然后她杀了大灰狼
and then she kills the wolf.
看来有人是格林兄弟的大粉丝
Someone's a Brothers Grimm fan.
是的  他们从不粉饰太平
Oh, yeah. They didn't sugarcoat it.
他们知道与其说是童话
They understood that fairy tales
不如说是恐怖故事
are pretty much horror stories.
正是如此  所以我们才需要童话
Exactly, which is why we all need them
助我们对抗未知事物
to grapple with the unknown,
所以童话才会挖掘我们原始的恐惧
which is why they tap into our primal fears,
像是独自在树林里或者被怪物吃掉之类的
like being alone in the woods or getting eaten by monsters.
童话不是恐怖故事  是生活箴言
They're not horror stories. They're life lessons.
做该做的事  才能快乐幸福地生活下去
If you do the right thing, you get to live happily ever after.
只在童话里才会如此
But only in fairy tales.
说到童话  我们的死者
Speaking of fairy tales, turns out that our victim
还真的是小红帽
really was red riding hood.
你跟卡塞尔一样疯癫了吗
Are you drinking Castle's kool-aid now?
不是  我是说她
No, I mean that she was
穿的确实是小红帽的服装
actually wear in a red riding hood costume
商标上就这么写的
It said so right on the label.
那为什么她半夜三更
Oh, okay. So then why was she wearing it
在森林里穿成这样呢
in the middle of the woods at night?
正往外婆家去吗
On her way to grandmother's house?
我想不是
Mm. I doubt it.
她外婆住在塔拉哈希
Her grandmother lives in Tallahassee.
太好了  你查明身份了吗
Oh, great. So you got an I.D.?
是的  在车管所数据库里查到了她的指纹
Yeah. Her prints popped in the D.M.V. database.
她的名叫艾米·摩根
Her name's Amy Morgan.
她姐姐莱斯利正赶来警局
Her sister Leslie's on her way in.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你是说艾米被什么动物袭击了吗
Are you saying Amy was attacked by some kind of animal?
你们知道她为什么去公园吗
Do either of you have any idea why she was in the park?
艾米从来不去那里  她没时间
Amy never went there. She didn't have time.
她太忙了
She was too busy.
忙什么
Doing what?
她是桑普森·布里格斯的律师
Sh-she was an attorney for Sampson Briggs
诉讼律师
litigation.
每周得干近百小时呢
They worked her, like, a hundred hours a week.
她有男友吗
Did she have a boyfriend,
昨晚可能会跟谁在一起吗
anyone that she would've been with last night?
艾米单身
Amy's single.
她一个人住
She lives alone.
她这人上进心很强
Um... she's very driven.
生前
Was.
她生前如此
She was.
你们知道她为什么穿着这个吗
Do either of you know why she would be wearing this?
这是什么  斗篷吗
What is it, a cape?
是小红帽斗篷
It's a red riding hood cloak.
她穿着这个吗
She was wearing that?
我了解艾米的穿衣打扮
I know Amy's closet.
这不是她的
This was not hers.
她的运动裤都普拉达的
I mean, even her sweatpants were prada.
那可能她是去参加聚会
Well, maybe she was going to a party.
她有提到什么聚会吗
Did she mention any parties?
我告诉你  她绝对不会穿这种衣服的
I'm telling you, she would never wear a thing like this.
莱斯利  你妹妹告诉过你
Leslie, did your sister ever tell you
她生活或工作上异常的事情吗
about anything unusual going on at work or in her personal life?
我不知道
I don't know.
我一周没和她联系过了
I hadn't heard from her all week.
这是算异常吗
And was that out of the ordinary?
是的  我们通常每天通话
Yes. We usually talked every day,
她没有打电话给我  我以为
and when she didn't call, I just assumed
她在忙案子什么的  可...
she was busy with a case or something, but...
或许她是有什么别的事
Maybe there was something else going on.
好  拜拜
Okay, bye.
谢谢  是莱恩来电
Hey. Thank you. So that was Ryan.
他刚离开动物管制所
He just left Animal Control,
最近公园只有一起动物走失报告
and there was only one recent report of an animal loose in the park--
一只小猎犬  叫弗雷德
A beagle named Fred.
那么要么弗雷德是一只狂暴的猎犬
Well, either Fred is one vicious beagle
要么另有隐情
or this mystery has just deepened.
一个精力充沛的律师
How does a high-powered lawyer
怎么会穿着小红帽的服装死去的呢
end up dead in a red riding hood costume?
艾米的工作压力大强度高  对吗
Amy worked long hours under high pressure, right?
那如果她有她姐姐不知道的
What if she had a secret way of letting off steam
秘密宣泄压力的途径呢
that even her sister didn't know about?
举个例子
Like what?
有一个成年角色扮演亚文化群体
There's this whole adult role-playing subculture
对童话十分痴迷
obsessed with fairy tales.
不  不是那种角色扮演
No, not that kind of adult role play,
不过  也有那种的
although, there is that one, too.
你怎么知道
And you know this how?
做过一点研究
Did a little research.
牧羊女啊
Bo peep.
反正  这些人
Anyway, these people
穿上特定的服装进行角色扮演
get dressed in the outfits, they play the characters,
甚至将故事重演
they even reenact the stories.
或许艾米当时就在做这个
Maybe that's what Amy was doing
但是事情出了什么大岔子
when everything went horribly and tragically wrong.
卡塞尔  这理论出乎意料的合情合理
Castle, that is a surprisingly reasonable
而且很有根据啊
and grounded theory.
是啊
Yeah.
坦白说  我对自己有点失望
Frankly, I'm a little disappointed in myself.
我们也是  兄弟
We all are, bro.
我刚才查艾米的财务支出
So I was going over Amy's financials
看有没有不寻常的花销时
for any unusual activity.
发现四天前  她从存款中
4 days ago, she took out $50,605
取出了50605美元的现金
from her savings, all in cash.
50605美元吗
$50,605?
提出这个数目的款项很奇怪  更别说现金
That's an odd amount for a withdrawal, especially in cash.
是啊  还不止
Yeah, not only that,
这五万块  不在她公寓里
but the 50k, it's not in her apartment,
也没法与任何近期消费关联上
and I can't tie it to any recent purchases.
联系她的银行
Contact her bank.
看他们是否知道她提款的目的
see if they know why she made that withdrawal.
如你所愿
As you wish.
蕾妮那儿有消息了
Oh, Lanie's got news for us.
我确实有消息
Oh, I've got news, all right,
不过我想你不会开心的
but I'm not sure you're gonna like it.
我在死者手臂上的伤口里
I found hairs like this one
找到了这样的毛发
in a wound on the victim's arm.
这不是她的  所以我查了DNA
It didn't come from her, so I ran D.N.A.
查到匹配结果了吗
Did we get a match?
那不是人类毛发  是狼毛
The hair isn't human. It's wolf hair.
淡定  卡塞尔  我还没说完
Simmer down, Castle. I'm not done with the story.
抱歉  还有呢
Sorry. What's the rest of it?
从伤口的深度和长度来看
Well, from the depth and the length of the gashes,
所有伤口应该都是同一只爪子造成的
it looks like the marks were made by only one claw.
独臂狼
A one-legged wolf?
我觉得不是狼干的
I don't think it's a wolf at all.
那怎么解释狼毛和爪痕
But the hair and the claw?
凶手想让我们误以为是狼
The killer wanted us to think it was a wolf
以摆脱我们
to throw us off.
所以死者身上没有咬痕
Which would explain why there are no bite marks on the body.
伤口是人类凶手用狼爪子抓出来的
The goshes were flicked by human killer using a wolf claw.
那真正死因是什么
So then what's the real cause of death?
我找到两个新的针孔
Well, I found two fresh needle marks,
都在死者后背上
both on the victim's back,
这可不是她自己扎的
so she didn't put them there herself.
她被下药了
So she was drugged?
有性侵犯痕迹吗
Is there any signs of sexsual assault?
没有  但是毒检
No, but tox results
查到了含有氯胺酮和氧可酮
turned up ketamine and oxycodone.
我怀疑凶手给她注射了氯胺酮
I'm thinking our guy sedated her with the ketamine
然后给她穿上了服装
Then dressed her in the costume,
但是麻醉药的剂量没有把她彻底迷昏
but the dose didn't quite knock her out.
所以说  她想逃离凶手的魔掌...
So she tried to run away from her killer...
他抓到她时
And when he caught her,
又给她注射了氧可酮  导致她死亡
He dosed her with oxy, and it was lights out.
药  还有爪子
The drugs, the claw--
这是有预谋的谋杀
This is murder, planned and premeditated.
凶手有意设计了犯罪现场
I mean, the killer staged the crime scene
好让人们想到小红帽
to evoke images of little red riding hood.
但是他为什么要这样做呢
Yeah, but why would he do that?
我其实不太关心为什么
Well, I'm less concerned about why.
我只关心是谁
What I'm wondering is who.
凶手一定先把艾米引进公园里
So the killer must have lured Amy into the park.
也就是说凶手一定是她认识和信任的人
Which means he's someone that she knew and trusted.
是啊  就像小红帽信任狼外婆一样
Yeah, like red riding hood trusted her cute little granny.
没错  莱恩  艾米的同事怎么说
Yeah. Ryan, what did Amy's coworkers tell you?
他们说她最近非常不在状态
Uh, that, uh, she definitely wasn't herself lately.
上周五一点钟必须参加的员工会议她没到场
Said she'd been acting agitated since she missed a
那之后她就一直显得很焦虑
mandatory 1:00 staff meeting last friday.
她说有私事要办
Said it was for personal reasons.
她也是从那时起不给姐姐打电话的
That's the same time that Amy stopped calling her sister.
莱恩  去查查她的邮件和通话记录
Ryan, can you look into her e-mails and phone calls?
我要知道她到底出了什么事
I want to know what was going on with her.
是
Yep.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
你得来看点东西
There's something you need to see.
在那儿
Right over there.
她手里拿的是我想的那东西吗
Is that what I think it is in her hand?
毒苹果
A poisoned apple.
她是白雪公主
She's snow white.
看来我们对付的是一个童话杀手
It looks like we've got a fairy-tale killer on our hands.
贝克特
Yo, beckett.
失陪
Excuse me.
她的医疗警示手环上有注明身份
Her medicalert bracelet got us an I.D.
她叫克里斯蒂娜·柯蒂斯  25岁
She's Kristina Curtis, 25.
住在上东区
Lives on the upper east side.
她有近亲吗
Does she have next of kin?
有个丈夫  名叫诺亚·柯蒂斯
Yeah, her husband. His name's Noah Curtis.
你们抽点时间去见见他
Okay, I need you guys to take point on the interview.
问问他对此是否知情
Find out what he knows about this,
看看克里斯蒂娜和另一个死者有没有关系
and let'see if Kristina was connected to the other victim.
既然凶手给这些死者
You know, if our killer's dressing his victims
都穿上了服装
in these costumes,
我们一定能找到生产厂家
I bet we can I.D. the manufacturer
查明凶手是从哪里购得
and find out where he got 'em.
好主意  你去查吧
That's a good idea. You run with it.
看这  肤白如雪
Here it is. "White as snow,
唇红如血  发黑如檀
Red as blood, black as ebony."
这家伙直接引用了
This guy is quoting directly
原版格林童话里面对白雪公主的描写
from grimm's original "Snow white."
也就是说重演童话的不是死者
So our victims aren't reenacting the fairy tales,
而是凶手
The killer is.
不过她并非死于毒苹果
Only this woman didn't die from a poisoned apple.
她有和艾米·摩根一样的注射痕迹
She has the same injection marks as Amy Morgan.
知道死亡时间了吗
Do you have time of death?
今天凌晨五点到七点间
5:00 and 7:00 A.M. This morning.
凶手杀了小红帽
So he kills red riding hood,
六个小时后就再次犯案
Then six hours later, he strikes again?
这个频率挺快的
That's a pretty quick turnaround.
符合连环杀手的特点
It's all the markings of a serial killer.
但是理论上来说
Yeah, but technically,
犯下三起谋杀才能被称为连环杀手
You have to murder three times to be a serial killer.
我们让他走不到那一步吧
Yeah, well, let's make sure he never gets there.
柯蒂斯先生  你最后一次见你妻子是什么时候
When did you last see your wife, Mr. Curtis?
凌晨五点之前
Just before 5:00 A.M. When she--
她出去慢跑了
She left for her jog.
她跟我吻别
She--she gave me a kiss good-bye.
那是我最后一次见她
That was the last time I saw her.
真不敢相信她就这么走了
I-I-I can't-- I can't believe she's gone.
柯蒂斯先生  她跑步的事
Mr. Curtis, this run she took,
还有别人知道吗
who else knew she was going?
其他在公园慢跑的人吧
Other joggers in the park, I guess.
她每天都去  风雨无阻
She--she went every morning, even in the snow.
一天不落
She--she never missed a day.
她跟哪个慢跑者有矛盾吗
She have problems with any of the other joggers?
没有  至少她没跟我说过
No, not that she told me.
她提过有人尾随或监视她吗
Did she ever mention being followed or watched?
你是说有人在跟踪她吗
Are you saying someone was stalking her?
现在这种情况
Under the circumstances,
看起来不像是随机攻击
this doesn't look like a random attack.
你妻子的职业是什么
What did your wife do for a living?
她在第五大道上开一家画廊
She owned an art gallery on fifth avenue.
是家族产业  从她爸爸那里继承的
It's family owned, she took it over from her dad.
你见过这个女人吗
Did you ever see this woman before
或是听过艾米·摩根这个名字吗
or heard the name Amy Morgan?
没有  怎么了  她是谁
No, I don't think so. Why? Who is she?
她是另一个被害人
She's another victim, Mr. Curtis.
她会不会是克里斯蒂娜认识的人
Could she be an acquaintance of Kristina's?
我不认识她  对不起
I don't recognize her. I'm sorry.
克里斯蒂娜最近有没有什么奇怪的地方
Did you notice anything unusual about Kristina lately,
比如她的心情  她说过或做过什么吗
Her--her state of mind, maybe something she said or did?
上周有件奇怪的事
There was something strange last week.
周五我们本来要一起吃午饭的
We were supposed to have lunch on friday.
但是她没来
But she didn't show.
之后她打电话给我  说她去了画廊
She called later to say she went to the art gallery
有些紧急事务要处理
for a last-minute emergency.
上周五  你们的午饭定在下午一点了吗
Last friday? Was your lunch at 1:00 P.M.?
是的
Yeah. Yeah, it was.
怎么了
W-why?
对于为什么没去赴约
Kristina lied to her husband
克里斯蒂娜骗了她丈夫
about why she missed their lunch.
她上周五没去画廊
She wasn't at the art gallery last friday.
画廊的人也不知道她在哪
They don't know where she was.
我们的两个死者  都在被杀前不久
Okay, so both of our victims were unaccounted for
在同一时间不知所踪
at exactly the same time shortly before they got killed.
她们到底去哪了
So where did they go?
还不知道  不好意思
Yeah, still working on it. Excuse me.
是的  我是莱恩
Mm-hmm.Yeah, ryan here.
说不定她们认识对方
Maybe they knew each other.
她们的家人说她们互相不认识
No, their family said they didn't know each other.
她们的职业完全不同
They had completely different careers,
住的地方也不近
and they lived in different parts of town.
似乎她们的生活从未有过交集
It seems like their lives never really intersected.
直到她们被同一个杀手杀死
Mm, until they both died at the hand of the same killer.
为什么要选这两个人呢
So why these two women
为什么要用童话桥段
and why fairy tales?
凶手是喜欢随机作案
Did the killer have some kind of a random obsession
还是这里面有更深的含义
or was there a deeper meaning behind all of it?
我觉得他想用她们的尸体讲故事
Well, I think he's trying to tell a story with these bodies.
只是我还不知道故事内容
I just don't know what it is yet.
也许是为了钱
Maybe it's about money.
克里斯蒂娜突然从她信托账户提款
Turns out Kristina raided her trust account.
猜猜她取了多少钱
Guess how much she took out?
50605美元
$50,605.
两名死者都在周五神秘失踪了一段时间
So both victims go awol on Friday
还都取了相同数额的现金
and both pull out the exact same amount of cash.
这绝不是巧合
That's not a coincidence.
这就是她俩的联系
That is a connection.
你能不能联系克里斯蒂娜的家人
Can you get ahold of Kristina's family,
看他们知不知道她为什么取那些钱
see if they know why she might have needed that money?
我去找丈夫谈谈
Yeah, I'll reach out to the husband.
谢了  莱恩  你有什么发现
Thanks. Ryan, what did you find out?
我可能找到了指向凶手的道路
I think I might have found the pathway to our killer.
白雪公主和小红帽的服装
Those snow white and red riding hood outfits--
都是由一个工厂生产的
They were made by the same manufacturer.
知道在哪卖吗
Do you know where they were sold?
我还在等服装的卖家名单
I'm still waiting for a list of stores that carry the costumes,
网店和实体店都有
both online and brick and mortar.
到早上应该就有结果了
We should have some answers by the morning.
感觉不太对  马库斯
This just doesn't feel right, Marcs.
把那把椅子移到那边去
Move that chair over there.
理查德  你回来的正是时候
Richard, your timing is perfect.
我们正需要帮手
We could use your help.
帮你们违背我的意愿移动家具吗
Moving my furniture where I don't want it to go?
只是暂时的
It's just temporary.
我们明晚要在这办我独角戏的
We're having a staged reading of my one-woman show,
舞台读本
here, tomorrow night.
真可惜你没有自己的工作室
Ah, it's too bad you don't have an acting studio
可以来做这些事
to do this kind of thing in.
等一下  你有啊
Oh, wait. You do.
那个小黑箱子一样的地方不适合做这个
The little black box theater is not right for this, dear.
我们需要一个亲密的环境
It needs something much more intimate.
会很新潮的
It'll be very avant-garde.
没错
Exactly.
我觉得这把椅子该放这里  马库斯
Now I think this chair should be here, Marcus.
我想营造出一种...
I want to create a...
亲爱的  你就不能阻止她吗
Sweetie, couldn't you have done something to discourage this?
我试过了  爸  但她让我担任舞台监督
I tried, dad, but she made me stage manager.
其实没你想得那么糟
Look, it's not as bad as you think.
也就二  三十个人
Just 20 or 30 people...
我们会把一切放回原位
And we'll put everything back.
这部剧对奶奶来说很重要
This play means a lot to gramma,
而且剧确实很棒
and it's actually really good.
现在我知道了很多我以前不知道的她的事
Now I understand things about her I never did before,
还有你的事
and about you, too.
我的
About me?
不不不
No, no, no, no.
这里  这里还需要再大点
This-- this space needs to be bigger.
演员需要大空间
An actor needs space.
"理查德一直有阴暗的想象力
"Richard always had a dark imagination.
他注定了要么做个连环杀手
He was destined either to become a serial killer
要么做个侦探小说家"  妈  真的假的
or a mystery writer." Mother, really?
只是稍微夸张了点
Oh, it's just a slight exaggeration.
那根据这段
And according to this,
你对我写作生涯的起步有关键的影响...
you're responsible for launching my writing career by...
你和我第一个出版商上床了
You slept with my first publisher?
卡塞尔先生  我相信凭你的才能
Mr. Castle, I'm sure your talent
你终究会功成名就
would've gotten you there eventually.
确实是我的才能让我功成名就
My talent did get me there.
我不是因为她才得以出书的
I didn't get published because of her.
其实在你出书之后  我才和他上的床
Technically, I slept with him after your book was out.
但这样写更淫荡点
This is just to be more salacious.
他那时不是和我差不多大吗
Wasn't he practically my age?
亲爱的  你知道我一直都喜欢年轻人
Honey, you know I've always loved younger men.
他们是如此的精力充沛  能跟得上我的"步伐"
They have so much energy, enough to keep up with me...
大多数时候能吧
most of the time.
我要...
I'm gonna...
去喝杯苏格兰威士忌
erase that image from my mind
以消除我脑海浮现出的场景
with a bottle of Scotch.
亲爱的
Oh, darling,
我还邀请了贝克特参加明晚的读本
I invited Beckett to the reading tomorrow night,
所以你们或许可能把这当做约会
so you two might want to make a date of it.
我该怎么办
What was I supposed to do,
拒绝吗
say no?
对
Yes.
为什么你如此抗拒你妈妈的剧
Why are you so against your mom's play?
因为她在篡改历史
Because she's rewriting history--
篡改我的历史
my history.
相信我  我是亲身经历过
Trust me, I lived through it.
她把这一切都改得像是她的个人童话
She's making it sound like it's her own personal fairy tale.
这么说  你不喜欢别人根据你的生活
Oh, so you don't like it when someone writes
写出他们眼中的故事
their own version of your life?
真有意思
Interesting.
你是在指妮基·希特系列吗
Okay, are you referring to the Nikki Heat books?
这可完全不同
Because this is completely different.
哪里不同
How is it different?
首先  我没说过
Well, for one thing, I'm not claiming
我所写的故事是真实存在的
that what I write is actually true.
她也没说过吧
Well, I don't think she is either.
得了吧  卡塞尔  你自己也说过
Come on, Castle, you said so yourself,
所有人都需要一个童话
everyone needs a fairy tale.
让你妈有一个童话又有什么害处呢
What's the harm in letting your mom have one of her own?
好吧  不如换个
Okay, let's-- let's change the subject
不会让我气得溃疡的话题吧
to something less likely to give me an ulcer.
神秘的50605美元查得如何了
How about that mysterious $50,605?
好吧
Okay.
我们几乎找过所有与艾米
Um, well, we talked to pretty much everyone
和克里斯蒂娜关系亲密的人谈话
close to Amy and Kristina,
但没人知道她们为何会取出那笔钱
and no one seems to know why they pulled out that money.
那周五下午一点  她们去了哪里
What about where they were at 1:00 p.m. on Friday?
在艾米的邮件和电话上
Nothing popped on Amy's e-mail
都没有发现
or phone calls,
技术部还在彻查克里斯蒂娜的电脑
and the techs are still going through Kristina's computer.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我们可能走运了
I think we might have caught a break.
我们查到了出售这些服装的网站
We tracked down that web site that sold the costumes.
死者穿的小红帽斗篷
The Red Riding Hood cloak and the Snow White dress
和白雪公主套裙都是八天前发货的
worn by our victims were shipped out eight days ago.
发给谁  你查到名字了吗
To whom? Do you have a name?
是的  杰米·伊萨克森
Yeah, Jamie Isaacson.
住在第11街和第7大道交叉口
Lives at 11th street and 7th avenue.
而且他不止订了两套服装
And he didn't just order two costumes.
这批货里还有第三套
There was a third in the shipment as well,
是睡美人
for Sleeping Beauty.
睡美人
Sleeping Beauty?
他还要再杀人
He's gonna kill again.
我们先找到他就杀不了了
Not if we get to him first.
杰米·伊萨克森  纽约警局
Jamie Isaacson, NYPD.
快开门
Open up.
-把门踹开  -好
- Kick it. - Yeah.
上  上  上
Go, go, go, go!
房间安全
Room clear.
这些诡异的玩偶
All these freaky dolls--
正符合我对这家伙家的想象
just how I pictured this guy's lair.
自从看了《娃鬼回魂》
Ever since Chucky
我就一直没法正眼看娃娃
I haven't been able to look at a doll.
警探  来这边
Detective!
你们非得撞开我的门吗
Did you have to knock down my door?
女士  我们自报家门了
Ma'am, we announced ourselves.
我正要来应门啊
I was coming.
我只是没以前动作那么快了
I don't move as fast as I used to.
女士  你认识一个叫杰米·伊萨克森的吗
Ma'am, do you know a Jamie Isaacson?
我当然认识杰米·伊萨克森
Of course I know a Jamie Isaacson.
我就是杰米·伊萨克森
I'm Jamie Isaacson.
你...
Y--
要吃糖吗  很好吃的哦
Candy? It's very good.
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
伊萨克森夫人  这里还住着其他人吗
Mrs. Isaacson, does anyone else live here?
没了  亲爱的  这里没别人住了
No, dearie, nobody else lives here,
就只有我和我的伙伴们
just me and my friends.
还有其他亲人会来看你吗
Do you have any family who checks on you,
或者医护人员
health care workers?
还有其他...人类朋友
Other more, um, human friends?
基本上就是只有我们  怎么了
Well, mostly, it's just us. Why?
上周你有收到一个包裹吗  伊萨克森夫人
Did you receive a package in the mail last week, mrs. Isaacson?
我常收到包裹
Oh, I receive packages all the time.
茉莉和阿比盖尔就是刚送来的
Molly and Abigail are new arrivals.
她们很漂亮吧
Aren't they gorgeous?
是的
Yes, they are.
那有收到过童话服装的包裹吗
What about a delivery of fairy-tale costumes?
童话服装
Fairy-tale costumes?
根据我们的记录
According to our records,
你上周在网上订购了三套服装
you ordered three from a web site last week.
真是胡说八道
Well, that's just ridiculous.
我要这些童话服装干什么
What would I do with fairy-tale costumes?
不知道啊
Can't imagine.
这么说  你没从网上订过任何服装吗
So you didn't order any costumes from the Internet?
我看上去像是喜欢浪费钱的那种人吗
Do I look like someone who's in the habit of wasting money?
我靠固定收入生活
I- I'm on a fixed income.
我留意到这幢大楼里
Well, I happened to notice that you don't have
没有门卫
a doorman for this building.
那你的包裹通常放在哪里
So where are your packages left?
大厅的邮箱旁边
By the mailbox in the lobby.
伊萨克森夫人
Mrs. Isaacson,
你是否留意自己信用卡上有过异常支出
did you notice any, uh, unusual charges on your credit card?
有人能拿到你的卡吗
Anyone have access to it?
除非他们对我"掘地三尺"
Well, not unless they're digging for gold.
这年头可要小心为上
Can't be too safe these days.
是啊
Yeah.
UPS证实  他们将一个服装包裹送去了
So U.P.S. confirms that a package of costumes was dropped off
伊萨克森夫人公寓楼的大厅里  但无人签收
at Mrs. Isaacson's lobby, but nobody signed for it,
这是买家的指示
per buyer's instructions.
还有更多坏消息
Here's some more bad news--
大厅里外都未安装监控摄像头
No security cameras inside the lobby or outside.
依我们的观察
And from what we could tell,
这幢大楼安保措施非常不好
the building's not terribly secure.
凶手八成知道这情况
Our killer probably knew that.
所以才把这里作为快递投递点
That's why he used it as a delivery drop.
如果他知道老妇人的信用卡号码
Well, if he knew the old lady's credit card number,
也许就是她认识的人
maybe he knew her.
可能  也有可能他只是在垃圾桶里
Could be. Could be he just found
发现了她的信用卡账单
her credit card statements in the trash.
老套伎俩  但很有效
It's old school, but it's effective.
伙计们  说不定
You guys, for all we know,
我们说话这当口  他已瞄准了睡美人
he's targeting Sleeping Beauty as we speak.
我查到了一些事
Yo. I got something.
还记得上周五克里斯蒂娜在午餐时不见踪影吗
That missing hour of Kristina's at lunch time last Friday?
技术部发现她在那天12点50分时
Tech found a map search on her tablet that day
用平板电脑查了路线
at 12:50 p.m.--
路线终点是上西区的格拉斯曼咖啡馆
walking directions to Glassman's cafe on the upper west side.
好极了  你们俩去咖啡馆
Okay, great. You guys go to the cafe.
看看是否能查出她与谁见面
See if you can figure out who she was meeting with.
知道了
On it.
同时  我要联系巡警
In the meantime, I'm gonna get ahold of uniforms
要求他们在公园里加派巡逻人员
and ask them to double foot patrols in parks.
不过他这次不会在公园里犯案了
Only he's not gonna strike at a park this time.
格林童话里  小红帽和白雪公主
In the Grimm stories, Red Riding Hood and Snow White
都是在树林里被发现的
were found in the woods,
但睡美人...
but Sleeping Beauty...
却是在自己的卧室里
Was found in her bedroom.
没错
Right.
好极了  这就把范围缩小至几百万间公寓
Great. So that narrows it down to several million apartments,
这还只是在曼哈顿范围内
and that is just in Manhattan.
讲不通啊
It doesn't make sense.
什么东西讲不通
What doesn't make any sense?
他的动机
His motive.
所有的连环杀手都是在表达他们的心理冲动
All serial killers are expressing some psychological impulse.
在他们内心深处
Somewhere deep down,
对他们的疯狂行为自有一套扭曲的逻辑
there's a twisted logic to their insanity.
好吧  说下去
Okay. Keep going.
在原版格林童话里
In the original Grimm's tales,
小红帽  白雪公主和睡美人
Red Riding Hood, Snow White, Sleeping Beauty--
她们尽管命悬一线
they all end up near death,
但最终都获救了
but were saved at the last minute.
看来他是想夺走死者的美满结局
It's like he's trying to take away our victims' happy endings.
对  不仅如此  他大可订购任何人物的服装
Right. Not only that, but he could've ordered any costume,
却唯独选了这几件
but he picked these.
他对细节很在意
He took great care in the details--
狼爪  苹果
the wolf's claw, the apple.
他是出于某种原因选择这些童话人物
He chose these characters for a reason.
选中这两个女人也是一样
He chose these women for a reason.
我只是  暂时想不出原因
I just... haven't figured it out yet.
不管什么原因  肯定跟她们
Well, whatever it is, it has to be connected
取的钱有关
to the cash that they withdrew.
或许是因为她们有健全的银行账户才被选上的
Maybe he's choosing women with healthy bank accounts.
银行
Bank.
怎么了
Sorry?
克里斯蒂娜和艾米都取了等量的现金
Kristina and Amy both withdrew the same amount of money.
或许睡美人也取了等量的钱
Maybe our sleeping beauty did as well.
国家税务局要求银行
The I.R.S. requires banks
上报任何超过一万美金的交易
to report any transactions over $10,000,
-也就是说有银行记录可查  -没错
- so they would have a record of it. - Exactly.
没错  她来过
Yeah, she was here.
上周五的午餐高峰时期
It was last Friday, during the lunch rush,
就在我把番茄酱弄到新买的牛仔裤上之后
right after I spilled ketchup on my new jeans.
我那裤子三折买的  超实惠
They were 70% off-- amazing sale.
她当时是一个人吗
Was she by herself?
不是  一共有三个人
No, it was a party of three.
三个  你记不记得跟她一起的两个人
Three? Do you remember who else she was with?
是两个女的
Two other women.
我还从没被警察问过话呢
I've never been questioned by cops before.
我能把这事发到推特上吗
You mind if I tweet about this?
这个  还是别发了吧
Uh, yeah, yes, we-- we do mind.
这是她的同伴之一吗
This one of the women?
没错
Yeah.
她们是罪犯吗
Are they criminals or something?
我感觉她们像是从上东区来的人
Cause I was getting more of an upper east side vibe.
不是  不过第三个女的可能处境危险
No, but this third woman may be in danger,
所以我们必须尽快确认她的身份
so we need to identify her as soon as possible.
她是不是用信用卡付的钱
Do you remember if she maybe paid with a credit card,
你有记下她的名字吗
maybe you caught her name?
没有  她们付的现金
Nope. They paid cash.
有没有一个男人跟她们一起
Was anyone else with them, a-a man?
没有
No.
你有没有注意到是否有人在盯着她们
Did you notice anyone watching them?
有一些顾客就盯着啊
Some of the other customers,
-因为她们在吵架  -在吵什么
- but only because they were arguing. - About what?
不知道  我想偷听来着
I don't know. I kind of tried to eavesdrop,
但是每次我走过她们旁边
but every time I went over there,
她们就狠狠地瞪我
they gave me the death stare.
不管她们在说什么
Whatever they were talking about,
都不希望被我听到
they didn't want me to hear.
国家税务局的报告
Okay, so the I.R.S. search
显示在当天产生过十笔
reveals ten different cash transactions
五万到六万的现金交易
between $50,000 and $60,000 for that day.
有两笔分别来自小红帽和白雪公主
Two belong to our red riding hood and ow white.
剩下八个人
That leaves us eight.
五笔交易的客户是男的
Five of them were made by males,
那还剩
Leaving...
三个女人
Three women.
杰西卡·哈珀  夏洛特·博伊德
Jessica Harper, Charlotte Boyd,
以及达娜·威尔森
and Dana Wilson.
哈珀和威尔森都50多了
Well, Harper and Wilson are in their 50s.
不符合侧写
They don't fit the profile.
那就只剩下
Which leaves us...
夏洛特·博伊德
Charlotte Boyd.
我们确定了上周五
Hey, we were able to confirm
克里斯蒂娜跟艾米·摩根
that Kristina was here with Amy Morgan
还有另外一个女一起吃过饭
and a third woman last friday.
我们觉得她很可能就是罪犯的第三个目标
We think she might be our killer's third target.
没法确认她的身份
We didn't get an I.D.,
不过我们拿到了一个细致的描述
but we did get a pretty good description.
我猜猜看  二十多岁  褐发褐眼
Let me guess--in her 20s, brown hair, brown eyes,
-很有异国情调  -没错  你怎么知道
- exotic looking. - Yeah, how'd you know?
夏洛特没接电话
Charlotte isn't answering.
她叫夏洛特·博伊德
Her name's Charlotte Boyd.
莱恩  我把她的地址发给你
Ryan, I'm gonna text you her address.
我们在她家汇合
Just meet us over there.
贝克特
Beckett!
卡塞尔
Castle?
叫救护车  她还活着
Call an ambulance. She's still alive.
好的
Okay, yeah.
任何关于她的消息都及时通知我  谢谢
Just keep me posted on her status. Thanks.
急诊室打来的
So that was the E.R..
夏洛特情况稳定了  但还没醒
Charlotte is stable but still unconscious.
体内有氯胺酮和氧可酮吗
Ketamine and oxycodone?
对  如果没有及时治疗  她的心跳就会停止
Yeah, and without that treatment, her heart could've stopped.
医生说我们来的很及时
The doctor said we got there just in time.
就像童话里一样
Just like in the fairy tale.
怎么  觉得自己成了白马王子吗
So, what, you're prince charming now?
如果水晶鞋能找到主人的话
Well, if the shoe fits...
说笑的  我很高兴能有个幸福的大结局
Nah. I'm just glad we had a happy ending.
只有把恶魔打败了  关在地牢里
Well, it won't be a happy ending until evil is vanquished
才叫幸福的大结局
and locked in the dungeon.
我们就快抓到他了
We're closing in on him.
是啊  可他还是棋先一着
Yeah, but he's still a step ahead.
我希望他留下了一些证据
I'm hoping that he left some kind of evidence behind.
我们翻了个底朝天
We've done a full sweep.
没看到50605美元
No sign of the $50,605.
一套豪华私人公寓  还有那么多钱
A luxury condo and that much money--
这女孩干什么工作的
What does this girl do for a living?
她是一名高级经纪人
She worked for a real estate firm
在一家房地产公司工作
as a high-end broker.
如果你想买套公寓  没个一千万
If you didn't have $10 mil to plunk down on an apartment,
她是不会接待你的
she wasn't your girl.
好吧  一共三名女性
Okay, so we got three women,
都是二十多岁  事业有成
all in their 20s, all successful.
上周五秘密会面
All have a secret meeting last Friday
之后三人都从银行取了一样数量的现金
and then pull the exact same amount of cash out of the bank.
或许她们一起投资什么吧
Maybe they were going in on something pulling their money.
我觉得可以排除大乐透的可能性了
I think we can safely rule out lotto tickets.
不  我们肯定漏掉了什么
No, there's gotta be something that we're missing,
能把她们三个联系在一起的细节
something that links the three of them together.
你们看看这个
Hey, guys. Look at this.
我在夏洛特的抽屉底下找到的
I found it at the bottom of one of Charlotte's drawers.
找到她们的联系了
We got our connection.
艾米  夏洛特以及克里斯蒂娜
Amy, Charlotte, and Kristina--
三名被害人都在
our three victims.
都扮成童话人物
All dressed as fairy-tale characters.
没错  那时的穿着
Yeah, dressed as the same characters
跟凶手给她们穿的衣服一样
that our killer dressed them as.
看看日期
Check out the date.
05年5月6号
"05/06/05."
七年前
That's seven years ago.
没错  也正好跟她们取的钱是一个数
Yeah, it's also the amount of money they withdrew.
没错  50605刀
Yeah, 50,605 bucks.
对  看看照片背面
Yeah, and, uh, check out the back.
谁是最愧疚的人
"Who's the guiltiest of them all?
付钱  才能见到明天的太阳
If you pay, you'll live to see another day."
有人勒索她们
They were being blackmailed?
七年前的那天发生了某件事情
Okay, so something happened on that date
将她们联系了起来
that connects them all.
也正是这件事导致她们被谋杀
Something that led to their murders.
拍这张照片的人是谁
So who's the guy taking the photo?
或许他能告诉我们发生了什么
Maybe he can tell us what happened.
鉴证组在这张照片上只找到一组指纹
C.S.U. only found one set of prints on the photo--
是夏洛特的  不过他们鉴定这照片
Charlotte's-- but they were able to determine
是过去两周内洗出来的
that it was developed within the last two weeks.
这都能鉴定出来吗
How can they do that?
照片是用机器洗的
Well, it's machine processed,
那种在药房杂货店里的机器
Like, you know, from a drug store?
照片后面有个机器印的控制代码
And there's a control code. Auto-printed on the back.
能从这个代码查到这家店的地址吗
Can we use the code to figure out where it was processed?
已经在查了
Yeah, already on it.
希望能查到是谁去印的照片
Hopefully, that'll get us who ordered the prints.
这张照片是七年前拍的
This photo was taken seven years ago.
为什么直到现在才出现
Why is it surfacing now?
关于日期的事你说的没错
Yo. You were right about the date.
那天确实发生了一件事情
Something did happen that night.
警方还有报告记录
There's even a police report.
报告里该不会记录了白马王子的身份吧
I don't suppose the report I.D.'s our prince charming.
当然记录了  他叫欧文·托马斯
Sure does. His name's Owen Thomas.
不过他不可能是犯人
But he can't be our suspect.
因为他已经死了
He's dead.
七年前被杀的  就在05年5月6号
He was killed 7 years ago-- May 6, 2005.
05/06/05
05/06/05.
就在他们合照的那晚
The night that the photo was taken.
那天晚上欧文还参加了
It's also the same night that Owen attended
一个以童话为主题的地下狂野派对
an underground rave, fairy-tale themed.
最后有人见到他是在10点45
He was last seen alive at 10:45.
但这张照片摄于11点23
But this picture was taken at 11:23.
他怎么死的
How did he die?
内出血加上体内大量的
Ternal bleeding complicated with high doses
氯胺酮和氧可酮
of ketamine and oxycodone.
这解释了犯人采取的作案手法
That explains our killer's M.O..
他当时磕多了俱乐部滥用药
Okay, so he's high on club drugs,
可什么导致了他的内出血呢
but what caused the internal bleeding?
车祸
A car.
他的尸体是在路边被发现的
His body was found on the side of the road.
法医鉴定是车祸逃逸
M.E. wrote it up as a hit and run.
没有目击证人
There were no witnesses,
因此没有线索可查  此案也就被搁置了
So the trail went cold, they never solved the case.
这不是《我知道你们去年夏天干了什么》的情节吗
It's "I Know What You Did Last Summer."
谁是最愧疚的人
"Who's the guiltiest of them all?"
犯人认为这三个女人中
The killer thinks that one of these women
有一个人要为他的死负责
is responsible for his death.
或许她们知道内情
Maybe they are.
这张照片证明她们是最后见到他活着的人
This photo proves that they were the last ones to see him alive,
但她们没有将此事告诉警方
yet none of them gave statements to the cops.
可犯人为什么直到七年后才动手
But why are the murders happening now, seven years later?
或许某人直到现在
Well, maybe after all these years,
才发现这张照片
someone found this photo.
埃斯波西托  你去查查欧文的家人和朋友
Esposito, can you look into Owen's family and friends?
也许这当中有人在为他报仇
Someone might be trying to get payback for his death.
没问题
You got it.
我们马上来
Yeah. We'll be right there.
睡美人醒了
Sleeping beauty just woke up.
夏洛特
Charlotte?
我是贝克特探长  这位是卡塞尔先生
I'm detective Beckett. This is Mr. Castle.
你感觉好点没有  能回答几个问题吗
Do you feel well enough to answer a few questions?
可以
Yeah.
能不能跟我们说说你被攻击的情况
What can you tell us about the attack?
我当时坐在电脑前
I was at my computer,
在听音乐
just listening to music,
接着
and... the next thing you know,
我被推倒在地
I'm being pushed to the floor.
你看见行凶的人了吗
Did you see who did it?
没看到
No.
医生说我被下药了
They're saying--they're saying I was drugged.
为什么会有人这样对我
Why would someone do this to me?
夏洛特  我认为你知道原因
Charlotte, I think you know why.
你们三个人都收到了这张照片
All three of you reived a copy of this photo.
艾米和克里斯蒂娜没有你这么幸运
Amy and Kristina weren't as lucky as you.
她们都死了
They didn't make it.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
但我们已经照他说的做了  付了他钱
But we did what he asked. We paid him.
你们有什么把柄在他手上
What does he have on you?
那天晚上欧文是怎么死的
Wh happened to Owen that night?
夏洛特
Charlotte?
那只是一个童话主题的晚会
It was just some stupid... fairy-tale rave.
我们只想跳跳舞  开心一下
Um, we were just looking to dance and... have fun.
欧文搞到了点"K粉"
And Owen had scored some "Special K."
那个劲儿太大了
That hit is pretty hard,
但是克里斯蒂娜有她妈妈的氧可酮
but Kristina had some of her mom's oxy
可以均衡一下
and said it would even us out.
不知怎么  我们都进了艾米的车
Somehow we ended up in Amy's car,
就是拍这张图的地方
and that's where this picture was taken.
欧文怎么会死在马路上
How did Owen end up on the side of the road?
他出现了严重的幻觉
He was having some seriously bad hallucinations,
一直在尖叫  还抓我们
just... screaming and--and grabbing us.
所以我们把车停了下来  赶他下去了
So we pulled the car over, and we made him get out.
我们以为他回晚会现场了
We just figured, he'd walk back to the rave.
但是第二天早上新闻在铺天盖地的报道
But it was all over the news the next morning
那里有一起交通逃逸事故
that... that there had been a hit and run
死者是他
and that he'd been killed.
你们为什么不自首
And why didn't you come forward?
我们当时还是孩子
Oh, we were just kids then.
我们都吓傻了
We were scared out of our minds. You--
你们要理解  自首我们会付出很大代价
You have to understand, we had a lot to lose.
我们家境优越  已经被大学录取
We came from good families, we'd been accepted into college,
我们做了个约定
we... we made a pact. And we said,
约定不会把那晚的事情告诉任何人
we-- we wouldn't tell anyone what happened that night...
以后再不往来
and that we'd never see each other again.
我不是在为我们找借口
Look, I'm not excusing how we handled it.
我们是很蠢
We were... stupid,
但是我们什么都没做
but... we didn't do anything.
有人不这么认为
Well, someone thinks you did.
你们怎么把钱交给他的
What did you do with the money?
信上说把钱放进巴勒克街和汤普森街交界处的
The note said to put it in a dumpster
垃圾桶里
at Bleecker and Thompson.
我们不希望有丑闻打搅我们的生活
We didn't want some scandal messing up our lives,
所以我们就照做了
So we did it.
我们把钱给他了
We paid.
为什么他还不放过我们
So why did he come after us?
巴勒克街和汤普森街的交界处
Okay, the corner of Bleecker and Thompson--
放钱的地方没有监控器
there are no security cameras at the drop site,
目前为止  也没有证人
and so far, no witnesses.
他面面俱到
He covered his bases.
我真的有点恼火了
I know. It's really starting to piss me off.
你生气的时候还挺可爱的
Yeah, and you get cute when you get angry.
但生我气就不可爱了
But not when you get angry with me.
我查了一下欧文家里的情况
So I took a look Owen's family.
发现一个有动机的人
I think I found someone with motive.
他有一个哥哥
Turns out he has an older brother,
很明显  他们关系很好
and apparently, they were close.
和死者有关系吗
Any connection to our victims?
有的很
Oh, yeah
自己看吧
See for yourself.
等等  他是莱斯利的老公达伦
Wait. That's Leslie's husband Darren.
欧文的哥哥娶了第一个被害人的妹妹
So Owen's brother is married to our first victim's sister?
是啊  这世界可真小
What are the odds, right?
也许达伦发现了他妻子的姐姐
Maybe Darren somehow found out that his wife's sister
与他弟弟的死有关
was responsible for his brother Owen's death.
或者是两家本来就是世交
Well, maybe the families just knew each other socially.
这不能说明达伦就是凶手
It doesn't mean that Darren's our killer.
的确  但我要说的事能证明
Oh, that doesn't, but this might.
鉴证组找到了处理照片的地方
C.S.U. tracked down where the photo was processed.
这张是一卷胶卷里的
It's from a roll of film,
那个人洗了三张照片
and the guy who dropped it off had three copies made.
店员描述的长相与达伦符合
And does the guy's description match Darren's?
不需要描述  他们有监控
Even better. They had surity cameras.
就是他
It's him.
我尽快赶来了
I got here as fast as I could.
有什么消息吗
So is there any news?
找到杀害我妹妹的人了吗
Did you find out who did this to my sister?
我先问个问题
Uh, first let me ask,
你妹妹和你小叔子的关系如何
what was Amy's relationship with your husband's brother--
我是指欧文
Owen?
他们是高中时期的好朋友
They were high school friends.
我们都是朋友
We all were.
这和艾米的案子有什么关系
What does this have to do with Amy?
欧文很久以前就去世了
Owen died years ago.
你见过这张照片吗
You ever see this before?
没见过
No.
这是艾米
That's Amy,
这是欧文
and that's Owen.
这两个女孩我不认识
These two I don't know.
-这是他出车祸那晚照的照片  -这样啊
- It's from the night that he was killed. - Okay.
你丈夫达伦两周之前把它洗了出来
Your husband Darren had it printed up two weeks ago.
你知道他怎么得到这张照片的吗
Do you have any idea how he got it?
上个月
Last month,
我们在整理我爸爸的阁楼
we were cleaning out my dad's attic.
找到了一个相机  里面有卷胶卷
And found a camera with a roll of film inside.
达伦很想看看胶卷上的照片  觉得有趣
Darren thought it would be fun to see what was on it.
你们不是觉得他和艾米的死有关吧
You--you don't think he had anything to do with Amy...
是这样吗
Do you?
我不知道你们在说什么
I don't know what you guys are talking about.
我没有敲诈任何人
I didn't blackmail anybody.
那你不认识这张照片咯
All right, so then you don't recognize this photo?
绝对不认识
Absolutely not.
这个人也不是你  对吧  达伦
And then... this isn't you, is it, Darren?
我能想象你的感觉
I can only imagine how you must have felt.
这么多年了  竟然发现自己的小姨子
After all these years, realizing your own sister-in-law
也许和弟弟的死有关
might be involved in your brother's death.
我们在皇后区你的储藏柜里找到了现金
We found the cash in your storage locker in Queens--
151815刀
$151,815.
诡异地恰好是50605的三倍
Which, by wild coincidence, is exactly $50,605 times 3.
欧文吸嗨了
Owen was high.
他神志不清
He was messed up.
她们明明知道  她们做了什么
They knew that, and what did they do?
她们把他扔在那儿
They left him there.
她们丢下他  任由他像动物一样被撞死
They left him and he died like road kill.
你本可以去报警的
You could've gone to the police.
报警干嘛  他们第一次调查得那么"出色"
Because they did such a bang-up job the first time around?
我只想让她们
I just wanted them to pay something
为她们的所作所为付出代价
for what they did.
我甚至想要用这笔钱
I was even gonna use the money
以欧文的名义建立一个奖学金基金会
to set up a scholarship fund in Owen's name.
真的吗  奖学金基金会
Really, a scholarship fund?
那谋杀你要建立个什么
And what's your spin on murder?
有了钱还不够
The money wasn't enough.
你想复仇
You wanted revenge.
你想让她们像你弟弟一样死去
You wanted them to die like your brother,
穿着童话的服装
dressed in fairy-tale costumes,
过量摄入他服用的毒品
O.D.'ing on the some drug he did.
什么  我没有
What? No.
我不知道谁杀了她们  但是不是我
I don't know who killed them, but it wasn't me.
很难让人相信  达伦
That's gonna be tough to believe, Darren.
你有动机  你因为欧文的死怪罪她们
You had motive, you blamed them for Owen's death,
而且你还承认你勒索了她们
and you just admitted to blackmailing them.
我要求请律师
I want a lawyer.
你当然要
Of course you do.
达伦不需要律师
Darren doesn't need a lawyer.
他需要奇迹
He needs a miracle.
他妻子跟莱恩说
His wife told Ryan that
事发时他并不在家
he wasn't at the house when the murders were committed.
结案了
So that's it then.
是啊  这件案子结了
Yeah, for this case.
我们为地检官准备得够充分了  就差系蝴蝶结了
We did everything but tie a bow on it for the D.A.
这边请  摩根女士
Right this way, Ms. Morgan.
是真的吗  达伦
Is it true, Darren?
是真的吗
Is it true?
看着我说这不是真的
Look me in the eyes and tell me it's not true!
不  宝贝  我没有伤害任何人
No, babe. I didn't hurt anyone.
你勒索我的妹妹
You blackmailed my sister!
你骗我
You lied to me.
听着
You-- no, l-listen.
我说的是真话  我没有杀害任何人
I'm telling you the truth, okay? I didn't kill anyone.
我只想让她们给钱
I just wanted them to pay.
那是谁干的  你有照片
Who would do it then? You had the picture.
不  宝贝  我保证
No, no! Babe, I swear--
我的天  就是你
Oh, my God. It was you!
我发誓  我发誓
I swear. I swear. Babe--
你离我远一点
You know what? You need to get away from me...
远点
Right now!
听我说  小莱
Listen. Les--
你离我远一点
You've just gotta stay...away.
谋杀让活着的人更痛苦
Murder does more damage to the living than to the dead.
全都因为一个可怕的秘密
Yeah, all because of a terrible secret.
秘密就像是定时炸弹
Well, secrets are like time bombs.
终究还会爆炸
Yeah, eventually, they... explode.
卡塞尔  我不是原谅达伦所作的一切
You know, Castle, i'm not saying that I condone what Darren did,
但是我理解他
but I do understand it.
我懂想要复仇的滋味
Yeah. No, I understand wanting revenge.
但是他采用的方式好奇怪
The way he went about it doesn't add up, though.
什么意思
What do you mean?
勒索是远距离复仇
Well, blackmail is revenge from a distance.
谋杀却是近距离的  私怨的
Murder is up close and personal.
两样都做  没道理啊
It doesn't make sense he would do both.
别低估了他
Don't underestimate him.
他承认勒索的唯一目的
I mean, the only reason that he copped to blackmail
是想逃避谋杀指控
was to avoid murder charges.
和其他变态狂一样
And like any psychopath,
他是个好演员
he's a great actor.
-说到...  -说到变态狂还是说到演员
- Oh, speaking of... - Psychopaths or actors?
我想到了你妈妈
I-I was thinking about your mom.
原来你是指提到这两个词
Oh, so a little of both.
我们应该赶得上你老妈的演出
I think we can make the play.
当真要去
Really?
你想在黑暗恐怖的树林中冒险吗
So you want to venture into the dark, scary woods?
别害怕  卡塞尔  我可是带枪的
Don't worry, Castle. I got a gun.
我会保护你不被大灰狼吃掉的
I'll protect you from the big bad wolf.
你会为了我对我老妈痛下杀手
You'd use your gun on my mother?
我好感动
I'm touched.
多谢
Thank you.
谢谢
Ah, thank you.
天啊  卡塞尔  这称得上是个社交聚会了
Oh, wow, Castle. This is quite the soiree.
这是家族特点
Yeah, it's a family trait.
都爱把规模搞大  干杯
We tend to go big. Cheers.
干杯
Cheers.
-失陪一下  -好的
- Would you excuse me a moment?   - Yeah.
你来了
Hey. You came.
这对我来说意义重大  亲爱的
Oh, it means so much to me, darling.
她担心你不会来
She was worried you wouldn't make it.
老妈  祝你演出成功
Break a leg, mother.
抓紧时间  两分钟后开幕
We have a schedule to keep. Curtain in two minutes.
这个蝴蝶结总是打不对
I can't get this bow straight.
我来帮你吧
Allow me. Allow me.
我应该让阿丽克西斯帮我打结的
Oh, maybe I should have Alexis do it.
你这辈子都没打过几个蝴蝶结
I mean, how many bows have you tied in your lifetime?
但我每天系鞋带啊
Well, I tie my shoes every day.
还是你教我的  记得吗
If you remember, you taught me.
是啊  没错
Yeah, yeah, true.
蝴蝶结
The bow.
蝴蝶结系得不对
The bow was tied incorrectly.
我早说过应该让阿丽克西斯帮我系的
Well, I told you, we should've had Alexis do it.
不是说这个结  是另一个  她服装上的那个
Not you bow. The other bow. The one on her costume.
我们抓错人了
We arrested the wrong man.
什么  我不懂
What? I-I don't understand.
你是说达伦不是凶手吗
So you're saying Darren didn't do it?
他敲诈勒索是真的
Well, he's guilty of blackmail,
但他没有杀人
but that's as far as it goes.
那如果凶手依然逍遥法外
So what if the killer's still out there?
他来杀我怎么办
What if he comes after me
不会的
He won't.
我们的警员全天候守候
We have officers outside 24/7.
我们会抓到凶手的  夏洛特
We'll find him, Charlotte.
我们只是
We just, um,
我们想要你帮点忙
we need a bit of your help.
当然  我尽我所能
Of course. Whatever I can do.
我们认为抓到真凶的关键
Well, we think that the key to finding the real kill
是要弄清欧文被撞死的那天晚上
is through understanding exactly what happened
到底发生了什么
the night of Owen's death.
你能回答几个问题吗
Can you answer a few questions?
好吧  尽量吧
Y-yeah. I mean, I guess so,
但我把知道的都告诉你们了
though I'm pretty sure I told you everything I know.
上次我们谈话时  你说所有人
Well, last time we spoke, you said that everyone
都在艾米的车上
was in Amy's car?
是的
Right.
开车的是谁
And who was driving?
艾米  怎么
She was. Why?
我们调查了一下
Well, we did a little checking.
欧文去世次日
The day after Owen died,
艾米把她的车带到汽车修理店
Amy brought her car to a body shop.
车子的护栅和保险杠都坏了
She had a broken grille and a dented bumper.
知道是怎么损坏的吗
Any idea how she got those dents?
夏洛特  那天晚上到底发生了什么
Charlotte, what really happened that night?
欧文有没有试图回到车上
Did Owen try to get back into the car?
可能艾米慌张了
Maybe Amy panicked,
离开时不小心撞到他了
Accidentally hitting him as she drove away?
夏洛特
Charlotte?
我祈求艾米掉头的
I begged Amy to go back.
克里斯蒂娜和我都劝的
Kristina and I both did.
我们求她掉头  但她仍然径直开
We begged her, but she just kept driving.
她不是有意要撞他的
She didn't mean to hurt him.
是场意外
It was just an accident.
这就是真相
That's the truth. That's what really happened.
真的吗
Is it?
看看这些蝴蝶结
Take a look at how the bows
都是怎样系在被害人的服装上的
are tied on the victims' costumes.
怎么了
What about them?
这些蝴蝶结是凶手系的
Well, the killer tied these bows
在被害人被下药之后
after the victims were drugged.
注意蝴蝶结的样式
See how they look,
都是完美的水平
How the loops are pleasingly horizontal?
再来看看系在你睡美人服装上的蝴蝶结
Now... look at the bow on your sleeping beauty outfit.
蝴蝶结却是竖直的
See how the loops are vertical?
有点奇怪
It's a little weird.
如果三个蝴蝶结都是凶手系的
I mean, if the killer tied all three bows,
为什么偏偏你的与别人的不同
Why would yours be different?
因为这三个蝴蝶结都是你系的
It's because you tied all three bows.
这个不同是因为这是你给自己系的
This one is different because you tied it on yourself
系到身后
behind your back.
不  我被攻击了
No. I was attacked.
我是被害人
I am a victim.
但医生说你只摄入了
Yet, your doctor said you received
相当于其他女孩体内一半剂量的氧可酮
half the dose of oxy that the other girls got,
不致死的剂量
A nonlethal dose.
当我们把车停到你家门外
How soon after we pulled up
你过了多久想出给自己注射毒品的
outside of your building did you give yourself that shot?
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
我为什么要制造自己被袭击的假象
Why would I fake an attack on myself?
这样就没人会怀疑
So no one would suspect you
你杀害了目睹你罪行仅有的两个目击证人
of silencing the only two witnesses to your crime.
你们在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
当时克里斯蒂娜和艾米
At the time, Kristina and Amy
都同意帮你保守秘密
were willing to bury your secret,
但后来
But then...
这张照片出现了
This photo showed up.
你还能再指望她们保守多久呢
I mean, how long could you expect them to keep the secret,
尤其是犯案的人是你
Especially since you were at fault?
你所想的只有这桩丑事
All you could think about was the scandal--
监狱会毁了你的人生
Jail, how it would ruin your life--
都是因为克里斯蒂娜和艾米知道真相
All because Kristina and Amy knew the truth.
夏洛特
Charlotte,
当天艾米的车是你驾驶的
you were behind the wheel in Amy's car.
是你开车撞了欧文  导致他的死亡
It was you that hit and killed Owen.
不  我说了  车是艾米开的
No, Amy was driving. I told you.
那为什么汽车修理费是你支付的
Then why did you pay for the car repairs?
我们有收据
We have the receipt.
你们不知道那天晚上发生了什么
You don't know what happened that night.
你们证明不了我撞了欧文
You can't prove that I hit Owen,
你们也证明不了我杀了艾米和克里斯蒂娜
and you can't prove that I killed Amy or Kristina.
我能
Yes, I can.
你的事务所处理了一位年迈女士
Your firm handled the reverse mortgage
杰米·伊萨克森的反向抵押贷款业务
of an old woman named Jamie Isaacson.
她用信用卡支付了服装费
She paid closing costs with her credit card.
而那就是你用来
That's the same credit card
支付那三套服装的信用卡
that you used to pay for all three costumes.
夏洛特·博伊德你因谋杀
Charlotte Boyd, you are under arrest
艾米·摩根
for the murders of Amy Morgan...
克里斯蒂娜·柯蒂斯
Kristina Curtis,
和过失杀死欧文·托马斯被捕
and the wrongful death of Owen Thomas.
蝴蝶结
The bows?
就这么露陷了
Seriously?
她其实是完美的童话坏蛋
She's actually the perfect fairy-tale villain.
好比大灰狼
Like the big bad wolf,
把自己伪装成无辜的人
she disguised herself as an innocent,
又好比白雪公主里的邪恶继母
but like snow white's evil stepmother,
她不择手段  甚至杀戮
she was willing to do anything, even kill,
只为了保护自己形象
to protect her image.
这么多年过去了
After all these years,
也许欧文的家人终于可以释怀了
maybe Owen's family can have some closure about his death.
但是代价呢
Yeah, but at what cost?
两个女人死了
Two women are dead,
达伦依然被指控敲诈勒索
Darren's still being charged with blackmail,
我确定他妻子肯定跟他离婚
and I'm sure his marriage is over.
这就是我们需要童话的原因
Well, and that's why we need fairy tales
面对太多残酷的现实
in the face of too much reality,
童话提醒我们美好的结局依然可能
to remind us that happy endings are still possible.
好的  明早见
All right. See you in the morning.
-再见  -再见
- Later.  - Bye.
说到童话故事
Speaking of fairy tales,
我老妈要安可演出了
my mother is ready to give her encore performance.
该回到黑暗丛林了吗
Time to go back into the woods?
还带着枪吗
Still got your gun?
这是一生一次的好机会
It was the opportunity of a lifetime--
有机会在百老汇塑造
the chance to originate the role
一个邪恶的巫婆的角色
of the wicked witch on Broadway.
但这也意味着要离开家
But it would mean being away from home
一周演六个晚场  两个日场
Six nights a week, two matinees.
我该怎么做呢
Huh. What was I to do?
要知道这全是虚构的
Realize that none of it ever happened?
弗朗西斯·培根曾写道
Francis Bacon once wrote,
有子女之人
"He that hath children
已将自己押给了命运
hath given hostages to fortune."
如果我是人质  那么我的儿子理查德
Well, if I was a hostage, then my son Richard
就是我的绑架者
was my captor,
我的奴役者
my enslaver.
我人可就在这呢
Hey, I'm right here.
我没有接演那个角色  我拒绝了财富
I turned down the role, turned my back on fortune.
这
And...
是我职业生涯最棒的一次抉择
it was the best career move I ever made,
因为一个更伟大的角色出现在我面前
for an even greater role came my way...
这个角色
A part--
可能是我此生扮演过的最伟大的角色
perhaps the greatest role that I have ever played--
那就是
That...
母亲
Of mother.
太感人了
That's sweet.
你说得没错  很感人
You're right. Thats sweet.
抱歉
Sorry.
如果理查德
Now if Richard
扮演儿子这个角色时  也能像我一样
had only been able to embrace the role of son
倾注那么多心血就好了
with the same level of commitment.
果然还是回到了黑暗森林
And into the woods we go.